<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bio Hub</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_0_zink">Zinc is an important mineral that is involved in many processes in our body. Lack of zinc in the body leads to a number of disorders. Here are a few of the most common: irritability, fatigue, memory impairment, depressive states, decreased insulin levels, allergic diseases. At the moment, there are many scientific publications that clearly show that zinc deficiency reduces immunity. This happens as a result of a decrease in the number of T-lymphocytes — these lymphocytes recognize and destroy foreign and potentially dangerous substances. In a number of studies, scientists have found that taking 45 mg of zinc in people with low concentrations of zinc in the blood during the year leads to a 50% reduction in the frequency of upper respiratory tract infections. In addition, zinc is involved in processes that affect our mood by increasing the uptake of serotonin in certain areas of the brain. In people with depression, there is a decrease in the concentration of circulating zinc in the blood serum. And the worse the symptoms of depression, the lower the zinc concentration. Zinc deficiency also reduces the activity of brain neurotrophic factor (BDNF) — this protein is involved in the regulation of growth and plasticity of neurons. A decrease in BDNF activity leads to a decrease in memory and depression. Zinc deficiency reduces appetite, and this is usually the first symptom of zinc deficiency. Depressive symptoms soon follow. Zinc deficiency also reduces testosterone synthesis, so this element is especially important for men. Zinc has two standard dosages. The low dosage is 5-10 mg, and the high dosage is 25-45 mg. A low dose works well as a daily prophylactic, while a high dose should be taken by those with zinc deficiency. During periods of active sexual life , the daily need for zinc in men increases to 70 mg. Most zinc is found in pumpkin seeds, sesame seeds, pine nuts, meat, lentils, peanuts, hard cheeses, oats, cocoa. So do not forget to include such products in the diet, well, or take supplements containing zinc.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_1_magnesium">Magnesium (Mg, Magnesium)\nHistory of magnesium\nMagnesium in the form of a metal was first obtained by Humphrey Davy in 1808. An English chemist carried out an electrolysis process between a wet mixture of white magnesia and mercury oxide, resulting in an alloy of mercury with an unknown metal (amalgam). After distilling mercury, Davy received a new substance - a metal powder, which was called magnesium (calorizator). Two decades later, in 1828, the Frenchman A. Bussy obtained pure metallic magnesium.\nGeneral characteristics of magnesium\nMagnesium is an element of the main subgroup II of group III of the periodic table of D.I. Mendeleev\'s periodic system of chemical elements, has atomic number 12 and atomic mass 24.305. The accepted designation is Mg (from the Latin Magnesium).\n\nBeing in Nature\nIn terms of the amount of magnesium in the earth\'s crust, it ranks 8th among minerals, it is very common. Natural sources of magnesium are seawater, fossil mineral deposits and brines.\nPhysical and chemical properties\nMagnesium is a light and malleable metal, its color is silvery-white with a clear metallic luster. In its normal state, it is covered with a film of magnesium oxide, which can be destroyed by heating the metal to 600-650C. Magnesium burns, releasing a dazzling white flame and forming magnesium oxide and nitride.\nDaily requirement for magnesium\nThe daily requirement for magnesium depends on the age, gender and physical condition of a person. For a healthy adult, it is from 400 to 500 mg.\nFoods rich in magnesium\nFood contains different amounts of magnesium, we will arrange them as the content of the useful trace element decreases\n• * cereals (millet and buckwheat)\n* peas, beans, hazelnuts, tahini halva\n* powdered milk, watermelon, wheat bran, spinach, soy flour\n* rye bread, apricots, lemon, grapefruit\n* beef liver, rabbit meat, pork\n* wheat bread, corn, carrots, lettuce\n* dairy products, fish, eggs\n* potatoes, onions, white cabbage\n* tomatoes, green onions, beets\n* apples, plums.\nDigestibility of magnesium\nThe absorption of organic magnesium compounds mainly occurs in the duodenum and colon, with excessive use of caffeine, alcohol and potassium, the body loses a significant part of magnesium in the urine.\nInteraction with others\nThe balance between calcium and magnesium is important for the body, because these minerals are responsible for the normal condition of bone tissue and teeth. In pharmacy vitamin and mineral complexes, the amount of calcium and magnesium is contained in optimal amounts.\nSodium, magnesium and phosphorus regulate processes in the nervous system and are responsible for muscle activity. The metabolic processes of magnesium in the body occur with the help of vitamins B6, D, E and potassium.\nSigns of magnesium deficiency\nLack of magnesium in the body can cause kidney disease, stomach upset, taking diuretics and some contraceptives, excessive alcohol and caffeine addiction. Signs of magnesium deficiency include insomnia, irritability, dizziness, heart palpitations and blood pressure spikes, frequent headaches, fatigue, flickering dots in front of the eyes, cramps, muscle spasms, hair loss.\nSigns of excess magnesium\nSigns of excess magnesium are considered:\n* diarrhea, nausea, vomiting\n* drowsiness, slowing of the pulse\n* coordination and speech disorders\n* drying of mucous membranes (in the mouth and nose).\nBeneficial properties of magnesium and its effect on the body\nMagnesium is important for the effective functioning of nerves and muscles, it is important for the conversion of blood sugar into energy. Magnesium supports healthy teeth, helps prevent calcium deposits, kidney stones and gallbladder, and brings relief from indigestion. The human body contains approximately 21 g of magnesium.\nMagnesium normalizes the activity of the cardiovascular and endocrine systems of the body, brain function, helps in the elimination of toxins and heavy metals.\nThe use of magnesium in life\nMagnesium compounds (alloys) are used in aircraft and automotive manufacturing because of the strength and lightness of magnesium alloys. Magnesium is used as a chemical current source, in medicine, military, and photography.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_2_curcumin">Curcumin is a yellow-orange pigment of turmeric root (Turmeric Longa), which is known to be the main component of curry seasoning. Curcumin is one of the most studied natural compounds in terms of its health benefits. Over the past 30-plus years, curcumin has been the subject of more than 8000 scientific studies, including high-tech clinical trials on humans. According to the results of these studies, curcumin has become one of the most popular dietary supplements in the world and is especially appreciated for its rejuvenating effect.\nAnti-aging properties of curcumin \nCurcumin is a powerful antioxidant\nMany beneficial properties of curcumin are explained by its ability to support the body\'s own antioxidant and anti-inflammatory processes.1 Substances that act as oxidizing agents (free radicals) cause cell damage and accelerate aging. Antioxidants — compounds that prevent cell damage - resist free radicals. \nFor example, if you cut an apple and leave it in a lighted place, the apple will gradually turn brown as a result of oxidative damage, similar to rust formed on iron. This oxidative damage can be significantly slowed down if you sprinkle an apple with lemon juice or any solution containing vitamin C and put it in the refrigerator. \nInteresting fact: the level of antioxidants in cells, as well as the level of food antioxidants, determines the different life expectancy of mammals. For example, humans live longer than chimpanzees, dogs, cats and many other mammals because we have more antioxidants in our cells and diet compared to other mammals. \nThe antioxidant activity of curcumin is superior to that of food antioxidants such as vitamins C and E, as well as beta-carotene, since these antioxidants are effective against very specific types of oxidants (water-soluble prooxidants for vitamin C, fat-soluble prooxidants for vitamin E and superoxide for beta-carotene). \nCurcumin also effectively protects against both water-soluble and fat-soluble oxidants (oxidants), as well as from other types of harmful molecules. It is very useful to protect against damage to LDL cholesterol, which results in the oxidation of LDL, harmful to the mucous membrane of the arteries and leading to atherosclerosis (hardening and blockage of the arteries).1\nCurcumin and regulation of transcription factor NF-kB\nThe health benefits of curcumin and its ability to slow down the aging process are by no means limited to its antioxidant effect. Many of the effects of curcumin are the result of its effect on the cellular protein complex known as NF-kB (nuclear factor \"kappa-bi\"). \nNF-kB is involved in cellular responses to stimuli such as stress, free radicals, heavy metals, radiation and oxidized LDL. All these stimuli can cause inflammation by activating NF-kB. Curcumin stimulates the proper regulation of NF-kB and, as a result, can help improve the body\'s response to stressful stimuli, which ultimately helps reduce inflammation and cell damage.1 This effect is useful in preventing aging-related cumulative cell damage.\nCurcumin and inflammation\nAccelerated aging of a person is characterized by a state of chronic, sluggish inflammation for a number of reasons. This process is usually called chronic mild systemic inflammation (\"inflamaging\"). A key factor in chronic systemic mild inflammation is a decrease in the function of mitochondria - the parts of cells responsible for energy production. \nAs a rule, with age, people experience a decrease in the number and efficiency of mitochondria. As a result of this process, the energy of the cells decreases, which leads to the leakage of inflammatory compounds from the mitochondria, as well as to an increase in the amount of cellular \"waste\" inside the cell itself. \nInside a single cell, there is a process that is used to deal with such accumulated cellular debris. This process is called autophagy. The term \"autophagy\" literally means \"eating yourself.\" A decrease in the intensity of autophagy is another distinctive feature of aging and is closely related to the work of mitochondria. The end result is that the accumulated cellular debris is not removed by autophagy, which ultimately creates a trigger for chronic inflammation. \nAnother unique rejuvenating property of curcumin is that curcumin protects and improves the functions of mitochondria, preserves autophagy and supports the immune system, helping it to properly process and dispose of cellular waste.2 \nCurcumin has also shown remarkable results in helping the body respond to inflammation in a way that reduces it. In addition, curcumin helps to improve the overall condition of cells. These positive effects have been noted in clinical studies.1,2 For example, drugs with curcumin promise to be incredibly promising as a defender of the brain against aging.2-4 Residents of rural India who eat turmeric in large quantities have the lowest incidence of age-related brain problems in the world. Of course, you can just consume a lot of turmeric (the main component of curry) with food, but taking a curcumin preparation provides a higher dosage that allows you to get better results. \nIn a study conducted at the University of California, Los Angeles, forty adults aged 50 to 90 years who had impaired cognitive abilities and memory were randomly assigned to receive Theracurmin® or placebo. Theracurmin® is a highly bioavailable form of curcumin and was given to subjects at a dose of 90 mg of curcumin twice a day (180 mg total) for 18 months.5 Before the start of the study, all subjects were assessed for cognitive functions, repeated assessments were carried out at intervals of six months and after the end of the 18-month study. The results showed that those taking Theracurmin® had significantly improved memory, concentration and concentration of attention. In the same subjects who took placebo, such improvements were not observed. In memory tests, Theracurmin® showed a 28 percent improvement over the 18-month study period. Theracurmin® also led to improved mood indicators, and PET brain scans of those who took Theracurmin® showed significantly less damage compared to the placebo group. These results, along with other studies, show that Theracurmin® and other products with curcumin may be the best choice for people looking for prevention of age-related mental deterioration and brain problems.\nCurcumin and Joint Health\nAnother result of aging is the destruction of cartilage tissue and other joint structures, leading to a subsequent decrease in joint function and mobility. Curcumin has shown impressive results in terms of improving joint health.6 Two of the most well-studied curcumin drugs on the market, Theracurmin® and Meriva®, have shown significant benefits in controlled human trials in improving joint health. In the first ever double-blind clinical study of the effect of curcumin on joint health, 50 subjects over 40 years of age received curcumin (180 mg daily in the form of Theracurmin®) or an appropriate placebo for eight weeks.7 According to the results of the study, the indicators of knee discomfort in subjects with moderate and high scores were significantly lower in those who took Theracurmin® compared to those who took placebo. \nMeriva® has also been investigated in detail for its effect on joint health.8 In one study, 50 patients with knee discomfort were given 1,000 mg of Meriva (equivalent to 200 mg of curcumin) for 3 months. According to the results of the study, the indicators of joint discomfort decreased by 58%, and the distance traveled in the treadmill test increased on average from 76 at the beginning of the study to 332 meters.9 In another clinical trial, 100 patients with knee discomfort were given 1,000 mg of Meriva for eight months.10 As in the other study, symptoms in percentage terms and walking distance also improved significantly.\nAnother small placebo-controlled study of people with mild or moderate knee discomfort showed that curcumin is useful in combination with piperine (a substance from black pepper that has demonstrated a certain ability to increase the bioavailability of curcumin). Six weeks of daily intake of 1500 mg of curcuminoid complex (C3 Complex®), which included 15 mg of Bioperine®, a standardized piperine preparation, led to a significantly greater reduction in discomfort while improving physical functions.11 \nIn a study with turmeric extract providing 75 to 85% curcumin without piperine, a daily dose of 1500 mg per day for four weeks also reduced discomfort, improved mobility and performance of the knee joint. The results were compared with the control group taking ibuprofen, with a fairly significant advantage in the direction of turmeric extract. The majority of the subjects (96-97%) were satisfied with the improvements achieved in the condition of the joints.12\nAvailable Forms of Curcumin\n</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_3_tianin">The amino acid L-theanine (gamma-;-N-ethyl-glutamine), naturally found in tea leaves and edible mushrooms Xerocomus badius (Polish mushroom). Green and black tea are made from the same plant. Black tea is distilled by fermentation, and green tea is not fermented. Green tea has been a fundamental pillar of Chinese medicine for more than three millennia and has been used by doctors both in combination with other herbs and as a hard-brewed drink to increase endurance and concentration. The amount of L-theanine depends on the geographical location of tea plantations, production methods and harvest time. In some types of tea, for example, in Camellia sinensivar (a species of the genus camellia of the tea family), L-theanine is contained in a higher concentration than in the well-known Chinese camellia tea plant (C. sinensis). There is also a synthetic form of L-theanine (Suntheanine™) on sale. \nL-theanine is widely used in Asian countries for the treatment of a variety of diseases and mental disorders, and is becoming increasingly popular in the West. The other main component of tea, caffeine, increases the concentration of acetylcholine and dopamine in the brain, which leads to improved attention, cognitive functions and increased mood. Caffeine has a positive effect on cognitive functions much faster than L-theanine, because it is absorbed faster, reaching a peak concentration in plasma 30 minutes after ingestion (for comparison: the peak concentration of L-theanine in plasma is reached 50 minutes after ingestion). In addition to L-theanine and caffeine, tea leaves contain other substances with many useful properties, including: amino acids glutamine, arginine, serine and alanine, as well as phenolic compounds epigallocatechin, epicatechin gallate, epicatechin and epigallocatechin-gallate (so-called \"catechins\"). Matcha is a special product made from green tea with a higher (compared to ordinary green tea) content of beneficial phytochemicals. \nAnimal and human studies confirm that L-theanine reduces the subjective response to stress, improves cognitive functions, improves sleep quality and protects the body from the development of chronic diseases, cardiovascular diseases, obesity and ARVI. Various components of green tea, including L-theanine, caffeine and catechins, can help prevent metabolic syndrome and obesity. L-theanine reduces oxidative damage caused by reactive oxygen species (i.e. \"free radicals\"), increases the concentration of glutathione in the liver and the effectiveness of liver enzymes (for example, superoxide dismutase) in removing toxins from the blood. Research results show that L-theanine has anti-aging properties. Green tea catechins can have a beneficial antimicrobial and antiviral effect. Studies have shown that in the gastrointestinal tract, green tea activates intracellular antioxidants and inhibits the formation of procarcinogens.\nL-theanine and neuropsychiatric disorders\nL-theanine has a proven ability to improve learning ability, memory and cognitive function, as well as enhance selective attention while performing mental activity tasks. Epidemiological studies confirm that regular consumption of Chinese camellia leaf tea (Camellia sinensis) is associated with a slowdown in cognitive decline, an increase in mood and an improvement in the ability to cope with stress. L-theanine is a promising drug for improving the effectiveness of therapy for schizophrenia, and may have a beneficial effect on the course of affective disorders, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), and is also effective in the treatment of panic disorder, obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) and bipolar disorder.\nIn the course of placebo-controlled studies, the effect of L-theanine (alone and in combination with caffeine) on mood and cognitive performance was studied and it was concluded that cognitive functions improved in response to therapy with a combined drug, but not in response to L-theanine itself. Data from two meta-analyses of the effectiveness of intervention in relation to the acute psychoactive effects of tea components on mood and cognitive functions showed that L-theanine improves the patient\'s perceived degree of relaxation, reduces subjective feelings of tension, and caffeine invigorates, improves concentration and increases productivity when solving complex cognitive tasks. \nAnimal studies confirm that L-theanine quickly crosses the blood-brain barrier, increases the level of serotonin, GABA and dopamine in the brain, binds to glutamate and NMDA receptors and can increase the level of brain neurotrophic factor (BDNF). Prolonged use of L-theanine (over 3-4 weeks) may have an overall positive effect on neuroprotectors, expressed in an increase in the synthesis of brain neurotrophic factor (BDNF) in the hippocampus – the area of the brain that plays a central role in memory consolidation. All these effects are believed to lead to a decrease in anxiety. \nSince L-theanine, as a rule, enters the body together with caffeine and other biologically active components of tea, most researchers have studied the combined effects of L-theanine and caffeine on mood and cognitive functions. \nL-theanine, anxiety and stress\nThe calming effect of L-theanine is an intermediate of many processes and mechanisms, including enhancing alpha-wave activity of the brain, increasing GABA synthesis, and also plays a role as a weak antagonist of glutamate AMPA receptors. The general calming properties of L-theanine are expressed in an increase in the electrical activity of the brain in the alpha frequency range (from 8 to 13 Hz). The changes in brain electrical activity measured by electroencephalography (EEG) are dose-dependent and similar to the beneficial EEG changes observed during meditation, including an increase in alpha waves in the occipital and parietal regions. Studies have shown that the increase in alpha activity of the brain lasted for 60 minutes after administration of a dose of 200 mg of L-theanine, and this effect was more pronounced in individuals with increased personal anxiety. Finally, the study found that digesting green tea with a high content of L-theanine reduces adrenal hypertrophy in mice exposed to chronic stress.\nL-theanine does not cause drowsiness, slow reflexes and does not impair concentration, does not carry the risk of addiction or addiction. No serious adverse side effects or interactions between L-theanine and psychotropic drugs or other natural products have been reported. \nThe results of studies on the effect of L-theanine on reactive anxiety are contradictory. The differences in conclusions are probably related to the different groups of patients examined, as well as the fact that some studies have studied caffeine in combination with L-theanine. A placebo-controlled study in which the intake of 200 mg / day of L-theanine was compared with the intake of benzodiazepine alprazolam revealed the presence of a general anxiolytic effect, but did not reveal a decrease in the experimentally induced state of anxiety. Two other studies, on the contrary, reported a significant reduction in indicators of subjective stress, such as a decrease in heart rate and blood pressure, in response to the same dose of L-theanine. During a 4-week placebo-controlled trial (N=30), a randomized group of adult participants without mental illness took L-theanine at a dosage of 200 m/day. The subjects noted a significant reduction in anxiety and improved sleep compared to the placebo group. In a small placebo-controlled trial, a randomized portion of 16 healthy adult volunteers took L-theanine at a dosage of 200 mg/day, and the other part of the group took 1 mg alprazolam. Participants were observed in a relaxed state and in an experimentally induced state of acute anxiety. L-theanine had some calming effect in the baseline state, but neither alprazolam nor L-theanine demonstrated an anxiolytic effect that would exceed the placebo effect both in a relaxed state and in a state of experimentally induced anxiety. \nL-theanine and other mental disorders\nA placebo-controlled study showed that taking L-theanine at a dosage of 100 mg twice a day significantly improves the quality of sleep in boys with ADHD; it is suggested that L-theanine may be an effective adjunctive therapy for ADHD. L-theanine does not cause drowsiness, while taking 200 mg of L-theanine before bedtime can improve sleep quality by reducing excitability \nNew data confirm that L-theanine can have a beneficial effect on the symptoms of depressed mood and psychosis. An 8-week open clinical trial (N=20) involved adults diagnosed with major depressive disorder who took 250 mg of L-theanine per day. Subjects reported improved mood, decreased anxiety, and improved sleep quality. \n</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_4_bioperine">Bioperine is used by companies producing sports supplements and nutrition to increase the digestibility of the active components included in their composition, as well as to increase their bioavailability. It is a 95% extract of the substance piperine, obtained from the seeds of black pepper.\nThe special effect of bioperine is due to its ability to activate the bioavailability of food components, improving their transport into the bloodstream through interaction with intestinal epithelial cells, during which their absorption capacity increases. According to the conducted studies, it was found that this substance improves the absorption of minerals and vitamins of different groups, regulates the level of insulin.\nIt has been proven to have a positive effect on the absorption of fat-soluble vitamin - carotene, water-soluble vitamins - ascorbic acid and pyridoxine, minerals - selenium and copper, amino acids - methionine, antioxidants - coenzyme 10 and others. The effects of bioperine are not limited to this list.\nNon-specific mechanisms for improving the absorption of food components:\nIncreased blood flow in the intestinal wall, which leads to improved transport of substances\nEmulsification of fatty constituents of intestinal contents\nAcceleration of active transport of substances\nAs a rule, bioperine is part of dietary supplements or specialized sports nutrition, especially fat burners, increasing the effectiveness of its other components. No contraindications and side effects from taking bioperine were found during clinical studies. It is worth noting separately that bioperine is not synthetic, but a natural substance – this is an absolute advantage over existing chemical analogues.\nThe average effective dosage of the substance is approximately 5 mg. No side effects were detected in the studies. It should be borne in mind that the supplement can accelerate the absorption of certain medications, so if you use any medications, consult a specialist beforehand.</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Biohacker \'s Handbook</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Setting</string>
    <string name="main_text_size">Text size</string>
    <string name="supplements">Dietary supplements</string>
    <string name="nootropics">Nootropics</string>
    <string name="bundles">"Bundles "</string>
    <string name="nootropics_fill_0">What is a combed hedgehog?\nA combed hedgehog is a very peculiar mushroom both externally and in its medicinal use. It has a creamy-white color and is not similar in shape to the most common mushrooms with legs and caps. Depending on the species, it looks more like coral or has needles, like hedgehogs, in a single stemless mass, and grows naturally in many places around the world. Since the popularity of this mushroom has increased significantly, it is grown on a small scale for both culinary and medical purposes.\nIt received the scientific name Hericium because of its spiky forms. In different parts of the world, it is also known as coral mushroom, houtougou and yamabushitake.\nThe combed hedgehog is used for medical purposes in the form of tea, tincture, powder or capsules. It can be eaten fresh, as well as lightly fried in butter or ghee ghee. It is recommended to collect mushrooms in the wild only if they are identified by an expert. In the markets, it is sold both grown and harvested in the wild.\nWhat are the useful properties of the crested hedgehog?\nScientific research of this fungus continues to this day. The crested hedgehog is most widely used to improve cognitive abilities or neurological health. There is also preliminary evidence of its benefits for digestion, antifungal activity, strengthening immunity, stabilizing blood sugar levels, improving anti-inflammatory processes, treating respiratory diseases, supporting healthy cholesterol and blood pressure levels, wound healing and prevention of various chronic diseases.\nSome components of this mushroom also suggest that it can contribute to maintaining a positive mood. Most modern studies have been conducted on rats, but there are studies on humans as well.\nTraditionally, the combed hedgehog was used in the treatment of ulcers, to support the body with general weakness and athletic training, as well as as a hemostatic agent for wounds.\nThe combed hedgehog is generally safe and has no serious side effects. However, if you are allergic to mushrooms, consult your doctor about the possibility of using a combed hedgehog.\n1. Nerve recovery and growth\nThe aqueous extract of the crested hedgehog contributed to the growth and recovery of the injured nerve in a study on rats. One Malaysian study showed that the crested hedgehog promotes the growth and differentiation of nerves in humans. Other studies have found that this mushroom is useful for diabetic neuropathy. Thus, the comb hedgehog can help in the treatment of diseases and injuries of peripheral nerves, as well as with the growth and health of neurons.\n2. Alzheimer\'s disease\nAn in vitro study of rat cells has shown that the extract of the crested hedgehog helps to reduce the damage to neurons caused by the beta-amyloid protein, which is the main cause of Alzheimer\'s disease. This indicates that the extract of the crested hedgehog can have an antioxidant and neuroprotective effect on rats. More human studies are needed, but this is a promising first step towards the potential use of the crested hedgehog for the treatment of neurological diseases.\n3. Mood and sleep disorders\nA review of scientific studies in 2019 showed that there is preliminary, indirect evidence that the crested hedgehog may be useful in the treatment of mood disorders. This effect may be explained by the ability of the crested hedgehog to improve overall neurological health, as well as its anti-inflammatory effect on the nervous system. This study recommends further study of promising data on the benefits of the combed hedgehog in mood disorders. The combed hedgehog can be a useful addition to a comprehensive treatment plan for mental illness.\nIn a study of people with a large body size, participants who also suffered from mood disorders, sleep disorders or overeating were given a combed hedgehog for eight weeks. The results showed that the crested hedgehog can be useful for depressive and anxiety disorders and improves the quality of sleep.\nIn a small placebo-controlled study of 30 menopausal women, it was found that eating a combed hedgehog for four weeks significantly reduced the symptoms of depression and anxiety.\n4. Epilepsy\nA study has shown that the crested hedgehog (Hericium Erinaceus) can help prevent nerve damage after seizures in mice. However, more research is needed to confirm these results and apply them to humans. Consult your doctor about adding a combed hedgehog to any standard treatment for epilepsy.\n5. Recovery after stroke and its prevention\nOne Taiwanese study on mice that had suffered an ischemic stroke showed that the crested hedgehog can help prevent brain damage due to oxygen starvation. This experiment further inspires other studies to explore the potential benefits of the crested hedgehog for nerve growth. Discuss with your doctor the program of recovery after a stroke and its prevention.\nLaboratory research on rabbit and human cells has shown that the component of the comb hedgehog can help prevent the formation of blood clots that can lead to heart attack and stroke. More research is needed to confirm these results in humans. Always consult your doctor about any methods of preventing serious risks such as blood clots.\n6. Cognitive functions\nStudies on mice have shown that eating a combed hedgehog can help prevent problems with spatial and visual memory.\nIn a small double-blind placebo-controlled study among Japanese adults, a significant improvement in cognitive functions was found during the 16 weeks of the experiment. The improvement in mild cognitive impairment continued to increase during the 8, 12 and 16 weeks of the study. However, after stopping the use of the combed hedgehog, the positive effect disappeared. More research is needed to study the sustained long-term effect of this mushroom on improving cognitive functions.\n7. Stomach and intestinal health\nThe combed hedgehog is traditionally used by different peoples in the treatment of intestinal ulcers. The effectiveness of such traditional use was confirmed in mice in a 2015 study. It was found that the crested hedgehog reduces the ulcerated area of the stomach of mice and prevents further formation of ulcers. Other studies of various digestive disorders in humans have yielded contradictory results, some positive and some negative. The correct dosage is very important, so consult your doctor about the use of this mushroom in the complex treatment of the stomach and intestines.\n8. Anti-inflammatory effect\nThe main cause or exacerbation of many chronic diseases is inflammation. The crested hedgehog gives good hopes as a general anti-inflammatory agent. In one of the 2015 studies that specifically studied the inflammation of adipose tissue and the use of combed hedgehog, it was found that it can prevent or reduce inflammation associated with obesity.\n9. Diabetes\nAnother study on diabetic rats showed that the crested hedgehog can help stabilize blood sugar levels, lower cholesterol and control inflammation, as well as improve other indicators of chronic diseases. The crested hedgehog can be included in a comprehensive plan for the treatment of diabetes.\n10. Maintaining healthy cholesterol levels\nIn vitro studies have found that the crested hedgehog can help prevent the oxidation of LDL cholesterol, which is widely believed to be one of the main causes of artery blockage. However, more research is needed to confirm these results in animals or humans.\nAn experiment on rats showed that the crested hedgehog improves lipid metabolism and reduces body weight for 28 days.\nAnother study involving obese rats who were fed high-fat foods showed that cholesterol levels, including LDL, HDL and triglycerides, returned to normal after taking a combed hedgehog. These results are promising, but more human studies are needed to make sure that this mushroom is a suitable tool for controlling lipid metabolism, weight loss, treating heart disease and high cholesterol.\n11. Immunity\nSome studies show that the crested hedgehog improves the immune system by stimulating the gut microbiota to activate intestinal immunity. Other studies show that it directly stimulates immune-specific white blood cells. Scientists are still studying how the crested hedgehog helps the immune system, but one thing is for sure: it can be a useful supplement to strengthen the immune system, in addition to good sleep, proper nutrition, effective stress management and exercise.\nConclusions\nThe combed hedgehog is becoming a popular remedy in the treatment of many disorders related to the nervous system and cognitive functions. It may also have other beneficial properties that are characteristic of mushrooms, for example, immune support, anti-inflammatory effect and general strengthening of the body. In addition, research is constantly being conducted on the benefits of mushrooms for many other body functions.\nConsult with a doctor or naturopath to choose a personal plan for maintaining your mental, neurological and general health, which can include a comb hedgehog.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_5_vitaminD3">Vitamin D 3 (cholecalciferol) belongs to the group of vitamins D (D1-D6) necessary to maintain human metabolism. Form D 3 is a type of compound that is synthesized in human skin cells under the action of ultraviolet rays of the B spectrum, and is also absorbed when ingested with food. It is a fat-soluble vitamin formed from tetracyclic hydrocarbons. In the human body, the substance accumulates in subcutaneous fat. Vitamin D3 reserves can be consumed gradually over a long period of time.\n\nThe vitamin content is measured in international units (ME): 1 ME contains 0.000025 mg (0.025 mcg) of chemically pure vitamin D 3. 1 mcg = 40 IU. To cover the needs of the adult human body, the average daily norm of the substance is 600 IU, for children under one year – 500 IU, for women during pregnancy and lactation – 1000 IU, for the elderly – 800 IU.\n\nRole in the human body\nVitamin D 3 is involved in the work of all organs and systems:\n\nRegulates the metabolism of calcium, phosphorus. One of the main functions is the mineralization of bone tissue and stimulation of the normal development of bones, ligaments of the musculoskeletal system in children. With the participation of vitamin D3 in the small intestine, calcium and phosphorus are absorbed from food or biologically active complexes. Thanks to the vitamin in the blood, the necessary concentration of trace elements is provided. The condition of hair, nails, skin and teeth also depends on the absorption of calcium under the action of vitamin.\n\nParticipates in metabolism. Vitamin D3 helps to normalize blood clotting, improves the sensitivity of cells to insulin and the absorption of carbohydrates, activates the regeneration of nerve fibers and increases their sensitivity, prevents the deposition of cholesterol on the walls of blood vessels.\n\nStrengthens the immune system. The active component of vitamin D 3 - cholecalciferol inhibits the growth of oncological neoplasms, stimulates the immune response when viruses and bacteria enter the body, helps fight inflammatory processes, and also prevents the development of psoriasis, eczema. Vitamin has a positive effect on respiratory function, facilitates the treatment of pneumonia.\n\nThe effect of vitamin D 3 on the development of children\nWith active growth and development of the body , the D 3 compound is necessary for:\n\nFormation of bone structures, ligaments, teeth.\n\nMaintaining normal muscle tone.\n\nStrengthening the protective functions of the skin at the cellular level.\n\nPrevention of rickets and abnormalities of organ development.\n\nReducing the risk of obesity, the development of diabetes mellitus, including the juvenile form.\n\nWith a lack of vitamin , the following symptoms are noted:\n\nLethargy, fatigue, tearfulness, irritability.\n\n Sleep quality disorders – superficial intermittent sleep.\n\n Increased sweating.\n\nDecreased muscle tone.\n\nBaldness in the back of the head.\n\nIf vitamin deficiency D 3 is not diagnosed in time, skeletal deformities and changes in the structure of bone tissue begin, rickets develops.\n\nSigns of an excess of vitamin D3 can be:\n\nMuscle spasms, convulsions.\n\nDigestive disorders, nausea and vomiting, abdominal pain.\n\nIrritability, decreased appetite.\n\nFrequent profuse urination.\n\nSigns of overdose with vitamin D 3 are nonspecific, therefore, when violations occur, it is recommended to conduct an accurate diagnosis to exclude other possible pathologies.\n\nMaintaining women\'s health\nMaintaining a normal concentration of vitamin D3 in women helps:\n\nStrengthen the immune system, including fighting infections of the genitals.\n\nRegulate lipid metabolism, maintain normal weight.\n\nBalance the hormonal background.\n\nPrevent osteoporosis during menopause.\n\nReduce the risk of atherosclerosis, diseases of the cardiovascular system.\n\nImprove the condition of nails, hair, skin.\n\nDuring pregnancy, it is especially important to compensate for vitamin deficiency, as it is necessary for the proper development of the fetus.\n\nVitamin D3 deficiency in women can be expressed in:\n\nInsomnia, headaches, high fatigue, hypertension.\n\nFragility of bones, teeth.\n\nMuscle and joint pain.\n\nHair loss, fragility of nails, deterioration of the skin.\n\nSystematic hypovitaminosis D3 can provoke the development of diabetes, weight gain, degenerative bone pathologies, joint inflammation, skin and oncological diseases, heart and vascular diseases.\n\nHypervitaminosis is accompanied by:\n\nWeakening of the immune system, disorder of the gastrointestinal tract.\n\nThe appearance of cyanosis of the skin.\n\nWeight loss.\n\nThirst, polyuria, frequent urination at night.\n\nMuscle rigidity, aching joints.\n\nChronic excess of vitamin D 3 can lead to the deposition of kidney stones, impaired bile outflow, corneal opacity.\n\nThe importance of vitamin for men\nIn the male body, in addition to participating in mineral metabolism and metabolic processes, the compound D 3:\n\nNormalizes the concentration of testosterone. The hormone is consumed to compensate for the lack of calcium if the trace element ceases to be absorbed due to a deficiency of vitamin D 3. As a result, the overall testosterone level drops, which is expressed in a deterioration of sexual function. Replenishing the vitamin level allows you to increase testosterone levels.\n\nIncrease muscle volume and develop muscle strength. Under the action of the vitamin, neuromuscular conduction improves, the consumption of fat reserves is facilitated and the intensity of muscle mass gain increases.\n\nImprovement of erectile function and prevention of impotence. The antioxidant properties of cholecalciferol affect the content of nitric oxide in the blood, which is needed for vasodilation. In parallel, the rheological parameters of blood (viscosity, coagulability) are improving. Sufficient daily intake of vitamin D 3 helps to reduce the risk of impotence and sexual dysfunction as a result of vascular dysfunction.\n\nSources of vitamin\nThe substance enters the body in three ways:\n\nIt is synthesized under the action of ultraviolet light.\n\nIt is absorbed from foods rich in vitamin D 3.\n\nIt is absorbed from vitamin and mineral complexes and dietary supplements.\n\nSynthesis in the body\nFor sufficient vitamin production, it is enough for an adult to irradiate his face and hands under the sun for 15-20 minutes daily. \n\nBeing in the shade or cloudy reduces vitamin production by 60%.\n\nClothing, sunscreens and dense cosmetics block the synthesis of the substance.\n\nUV rays of the desired spectrum do not pass through the glass.\n\nDespite the large number of sunny days, vitamin deficiency often develops in Africans. This is due to the fact that people spend most of the daylight hours in the shade.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_6_Iodine">Iodine is an important trace element used by the body for the synthesis of thyroid hormones. These hormones are involved in the regulation of metabolism, as well as control many other important functions, especially at a young age. It is important to obtain a sufficient amount of iodine during infancy and pregnancy, since this ensures the proper development of the musculoskeletal system, central and peripheral nervous system.\n\nIodine is not synthesized in our body and must come with food and water.\n\nIodine is unevenly distributed in the environment, the largest part of iodine on our planet is concentrated in the oceans. Iodide ions in seawater are oxidized to elemental iodine, which evaporates into the atmosphere and returns to the soil with rain, thus iodizing the soil.\n\nHowever, such iodization is not enough. Vegetables and fruits grown in soils poor in iodine contain insufficient amounts of it, and people and animals consuming food grown on such soils suffer from iodine deficiency. Iodine deficiency is a common health problem worldwide.\n\nIf there is not enough iodine in the thyroid gland to synthesize enough hormones, feedback systems in the body make the thyroid gland work more intensively. This can cause an enlargement of the thyroid gland - goiter.\n\nIodine deficiency and, as a consequence, a low level of thyroid hormones can lead to infertility due to the cessation of ovulation in women. Also, with iodine deficiency, it is possible to develop autoimmune thyroid disease, increase the risk of thyroid cancer. A number of researchers believe that iodine deficiency may also increase the risk of other cancers, such as prostate, breast, endometrial and ovarian cancers.\n\nIn a woman, iodine deficiency during pregnancy can lead to an increase in blood pressure. It is also known that iodine plays an important role in the development of the central nervous system. All over the world, iodine deficiency is considered the most common cause of mental retardation in children. In extreme cases, iodine deficiency can lead to cretinism, a disorder that includes severe mental retardation and impaired physical development. Severe iodine deficiency during pregnancy leads to an increase in the level of fetal and perinatal mortality.\n\nThe amount of iodine that should enter the body daily is determined by age. From birth to 12 months, a child should receive at least 60 mcg of iodine, children from 1 to 3 years - 70 mg, children 3-7 years - 90 mcg, children 7-11 years - 120 mcg, adolescents 11-18 years and adults - 150 mcg, pregnant women - 220 mcg, nursing women - 290 mcg.\n\nThe main method of preventing iodine deficiency is eating foods rich or enriched with iodine.\n\nIodine-rich foods include fish (for example, cod and tuna), seaweed, shrimp and other seafood. If the soil contains enough iodine, the food products grown on it, such as cereals, fruits and vegetables, will also be rich in iodine.\n\nFoods that are specially enriched with iodine include edible salt, milk and dairy products (yogurt and cheese), grain products (for example, bread and cereals).\n\nIn places where iodized salt and other iodine-enriched products are not available, it is recommended to use biologically active additives containing iodine. Many multivitamin-mineral supplements also include iodine.\n\nAnother possible reason for the development of iodine deficiency is the constant use of products containing goiterogens (goitogens). Goiterogens are substances that interfere with the absorption of iodine by the body. Such substances are present in some plant products, such as soy and cruciferous vegetables (cabbage, broccoli, cauliflower and Brussels sprouts). However, a balanced diet and the use of a variety of products negates this effect.\n\nIn addition, the deficiency of selenium, manganese and calcium in the diet also exacerbates the development of thyroid diseases in conditions of iodine deficiency (especially in combination with smoking).\n\nCan iodine be harmful? Yes, if it enters the body in large quantities (over 600 mcg per day, with sea cabbage - over 1000 mcg). With a high intake of iodine, the same signs may develop as with a deficiency, including an increase in the thyroid gland. However, there is practically no excess intake of iodine from food.\n\nIt should be remembered that dietary supplements containing iodine can interact with certain medications, for example, with antithyroid drugs that are used to treat hyperthyroidism. The use of potassium iodide together with medications for high blood pressure, known as ACE inhibitors, can lead to an increase in the amount of potassium in the blood to unsafe levels. Hyperkalemia is also possible when using potassium iodide with potassium-sparing diuretics.\n\nThe use of iodized salt is the simplest and most cost-effective way to prevent iodine deficiency, used by all countries in the world.\n\nIn areas with iodine deficiency, iodized salt is also used as a feed additive for cattle and productive animals. The use of iodized salt should be restricted only for people suffering from autoimmune thyroid diseases (Hashimoto\'s disease). To make up for iodine deficiency, in addition to seafood, it is necessary to use iodized table salt in an amount of up to 6 g per day (the upper recommended level of salt intake). Iodized salt can be stored for 6-12 months and the best way to use it is to add it to an almost ready dish in order to preserve iodine in the finished product as much as possible.\n\nIodine deficiency in the diet is preventable! A balanced, rational diet preserves the health of the thyroid gland and the whole body.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_7_Omega3">Fish oil is a source of Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA), which contribute to the normalization of cholesterol and triglycerides in the blood, thereby reducing the risk of cardiovascular diseases. The use of fish oil is effective in the prevention of atherosclerosis, hypertension, prevention of thrombosis, disorders of cerebral circulation, strengthening immunity. \n\nPolyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) are important nutritional factors because they are not synthesized in the body and therefore must come with food. PUFA of the omega–3 and omega–6 families are of the greatest interest.\n\nPUFA is involved in the formation of lipids, together with which they are part of cell membranes, affect the structure of skin and hair, reduce blood pressure, contribute to the prevention of arthritis, reduce cholesterol and triglycerides, reduce the risk of thrombosis; have a positive effect on diseases of the cardiovascular system.\n\nA clear relationship has been established between the daily intake of omega-3 PUFA and the degree of atherosclerotic damage to coronary vessels. At the same time, the more omega-3 PUFA is contained in the tissues of the body, the fewer manifestations of atherosclerosis.\n\nFish oil is a good source of essential omega-3 fatty acids.\n\nThe journal \"Lipids Magipe\" (1982) describes epidemiological studies that have shown that fish oil has factors that protect against heart disease. Eskimos eat food with a very high fat content and, according to the generally accepted knowledge about it, should have a high level of heart disease, but in fact have a very low level of them. When Europeans who ate ordinary Western food began to eat food that Eskimos eat with a lot of fish, they began to have positive changes in their blood. A low mortality rate from heart disease was found in Japan, where a large amount of fish is also consumed. Experiments with fish oil, first on animals, then with the help of clinical studies, established the same changes in the chemical composition of blood (clotting was within normal limits). In addition, the effect of fish oil on lowering cholesterol and triglycerides in the blood has been established.\n\nIn 1982, researchers at the Medical School (Michigan, USA) proved that fish oil reduces the reactive effect of blood on hormones. Clinical trials in Japan have shown that fish oil reduces the level of thromboxanes, which increase platelet aggregation and increase blood viscosity.\n\nStudies conducted at the University of Karlovy Vary (Prague, Czech Republic) have also shown that fish oil reduces high levels of triglycerides in the blood. People with high blood triglycerides were given about 18 ounces of fish daily, and they experienced a significant decrease in triglyceride levels and regulation of high-density lipoprotein levels.\n\nStudies conducted in 1983, it was possible to confirm that fish oil increases the time required for blood clotting, reducing platelet aggregation, due to which the process of blood clotting begins in humans and animals.\n\nOmega-3 fatty acids contained in the fish of the northern seas open up a new approach to the treatment of diseases such as heart disease, arthritis, diabetes, migraine and some forms of cancer. Final studies are being conducted, but the most curious discoveries have yet to be made.\n\nOmega-3 fatty acids\nOmega-3 fatty acids include a-linolenic acid, eicosapentaenoic acid and docosahexaenoic acid, which are present mainly in fish, and also in small amounts can be synthesized in the body from a-linolenic acid. In animals, the eyeballs, brain, testes and adrenal glands contain a significant amount of these specific acids (perhaps that is why some peoples consider these organs an unusual delicacy). Low levels of EPA and DHA in the diet can cause serious health problems. They are absolutely essential for many body functions, including the development and normal functioning of the eyes and brain. These substances also help to cope with inflammatory processes, for example, with arthritis, contribute to a decrease in the content of triglycerides in the blood, which are directly related to heart disease and stroke.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_8_Bacopa">Bakopa Monye is a plant with wonderful medical properties, which is part of the \"golden row\" of Ayurveda. For centuries it has been used in Ayurvedic medicine as a tonic for the brain and nervous system and to improve memory. In recent decades, scientific studies have confirmed the therapeutic effect of Bacopa.\n   It is the main means for stimulating and strengthening nerve and brain cells. Brahmi improves memory, increases life expectancy, slows down aging and gives strength in old age. Strengthens the immune system by cleansing and nourishing it, as well as strengthens the adrenal glands.\n   Bacopa Monnier has been successfully used in the manifestation of various disorders of higher nervous activity, in particular increased excitability, memory impairment, dementia, epilepsy, autism for more than a thousand years ago it was described in the classical works of oriental medicine.\n   Here is some list of what Bacopa Monnier contains:\n* Alkaloids\no Brahmin\no Herpestin\nBioflavonoids, non-toxic alkaloids brahmin and herpestin, as well as saponin derivatives (bacosides A and B) contained in bacopa Monnier have a beneficial effect on the metabolism of active mediators in the brain and special receptors that are involved in the regulation of emotional reactions, which, in particular, underlie depression.\n* Saponins\no D-mannitol, \no Gersaponin,\no Monnerin, \nBakosides accelerate protein synthesis in brain cells responsible for learning ability, memory and intelligence.\n* Also beta-sitosterol, betulic acid, xylote A, stigmastarol, numerous bacosides, among which bacosides A and B are responsible for the cognitive effect of brahmi, and bacopasaponins and other glycosides.\nBacopa Monye has antioxidant, antiseptic, rejuvenating, astringent, wound healing, anti-inflammatory, cooling, toning, soothing, diuretic, anti-cellulite properties.\nBacopa Monnier as a tonic for the brain\n\n* Stimulates the brain, strengthens memory, improves concentration, attention, gives clarity of mind, nourishes the brain, rejuvenates brain cells, normalizes cerebral circulation.\n* Relieves fatigue after strenuous mental activity, preventing stress, eliminates headaches.\n* Treats atherosclerosis, Alzheimer\'s disease, Parkinson\'s disease.\n* Helps to establish a balance between the left and right hemispheres of the brain.\n* Increases working capacity, learning ability, improves short-term and long-term memory, treats amnesia.\n* Expands cognitive abilities of healthy people, activates their mental activity, the ability to memorize and reproduce information.\nProtects the blood vessels through which oxygen enters the brain, thereby stimulating the flow of oxygen to the brain. After taking it, concentration improves. The students who participated in the experiments and took brahmi showed the best result in the exams.\n* In combination with Ginkgo Biloba, another powerful tonic, improves a person\'s intellectual and cognitive abilities.\nWe recommend that people after fifty times a year take a fifty-day course of taking Mind Max to restore memory functions and increase life expectancy. It is important for children to improve their mental development, as well as for the treatment of mental retardation.\n* Improves diction, treats speech defects. It is used as an adjunct in the treatment of alcoholism.\nBacopa Monnier as a tonic for the nervous system\n\n* Relieves anxiety, stress, tension, helps with depression, including postpartum depression. It gives a feeling of calm and relaxation, while activating mental processes. Treats mental disorders, acts as a sedative, eliminates anxiety. Normalizes sleep, treats insomnia.\nThanks to the restorative mechanism of action of bakosides, it contributes to the early elimination of the consequences of strokes, nervous shocks and traumatic brain injuries.\n* Beneficial effects are given by the use of the Pitt-type pre-natal syndrome, which is manifested by irritability, anger, a desire to argue, and sometimes outbursts of rage.\n* It is well used in the postoperative period to relieve stress and heal nervous tissue.\n* Brahmi has a positive effect for insomnia, headaches, epilepsy, neurotic conditions.\nTreatment of a number of skin diseases\n   Bacopa not only has an anti-inflammatory effect, but also helps to strengthen the vessels and capillaries that supply blood to the tissues, to the affected area, improving blood circulation and stimulating blood flow.\n   Due to these two properties, the plant is a highly effective remedy for the treatment of skin diseases, wounds, ulcers, cuts. Effectively fights psoriasis.\n   Contains an important ingredient asiaticoside, which helps to destroy the protective coating of bacteria that cause leprosy, allowing the immune system to successfully fight them.\nMedicinal properties of Bacopa Monnier\n\n* Promotes rapid wound healing, resolves old scars and adhesions and prevents the formation of new ones, thanks to the stimulation and regulation of collagen production, as well as its astringent properties\n* An effective remedy for cellulite treatment.\no Eliminates the tendency to overeating, and therefore, its use is useful for the treatment of excess weight and obesity.\n* Stimulates the body\'s production of glycosaminoglycans - substances necessary for the formation of connective tissues that hold fat in its place\no For varicose veins and chronic venous insufficiency.\no Glycosaminoglycans are also required to strengthen the tissues around the veins on the legs. Thus, Bakopa relieves tumors and pain in the legs caused by these diseases.\n• For lowering blood pressure, which helps with hypertension and chronic venous insufficiency\no For hypertension, use for all types of constitution.\n• To restore hearing\no Bakopa is considered in Ayurveda to be an effective means for restoring hearing. \n* For headaches\no It is the main means for stimulating and strengthening nerve and brain cells.\no Perfectly relieves many types of headaches,\no Normalizes cerebral circulation,\no Is used for mental anxiety.\n* With scleroderma (a disease in which tissue compaction occurs)</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_9_Glycine">Glycine is an amino acid that is a regulator that improves metabolic processes in the brain and nervous system, normalizes and activates protective inhibition processes in the central nervous system, reduces psycho-emotional stress, increases mental performance.\n\nGlycine is a part of many biologically active substances, including proteins of human tissues. Glycine is also a neurotransmitter, that is, it participates in the transmission of impulses along nerve fibers. Glycine receptors are present in many parts of the brain and spinal cord, they inhibit the release of neurotransmitters from neurons that transmit excitatory impulses to the central nervous system.\n\nGlycine regulates metabolism and provides protective inhibition processes in the central nervous system, reduces irritability and nervous tension, increases mental performance. It blocks the release of adrenaline and norepinephrine (the main stress hormones), cleanses the body of toxins and free radicals that destroy brain tissue cells. Under the influence of glycine, mood and performance improves, which has a positive effect on the adaptation of a person in the family and work team. It is able to significantly facilitate falling asleep and restore sleep, remove the effects of neurosis on the central nervous system, internal organs and blood vessels (decreases blood pressure drops, heart pain with cardioneurosis, blood flushes to the face during menopause).\n\nGlycine is prescribed as part of complex therapy for strokes and brain injuries – it significantly reduces their consequences. It is also used in chronic alcoholism to restore brain function and relieve the effects of toxic effects of alcoholic beverages. Glycine enhances the effect of anticonvulsants and sedatives. It also has the ability to reduce the need of brain tissue for oxygen (nootropic effect), resulting in improved memory and cognitive (learning ability) abilities.\n\nGlycine is well absorbed in the gastrointestinal tract, enters the bloodstream, and then into the brain. In the body, it is metabolized to water and carbon dioxide, its accumulation in tissues does not occur.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_10_5htp">L-tryptophan is an essential amino acid that participates in protein metabolism, promotes the production of serotonin (the \"hormone of happiness\"), melatonin (an antioxidant and \"sleep hormone\") and choline (a nootropic and antidepressant). Tryptophan is not produced by the body, so you can get it only with food or by taking special supplements.\n\nDeficiency of this amino acid can cause chronic insomnia, low mood, depressive states, eating disorders. In this article, we will tell you how L-tryptophan differs from 5-HTP, what effect it has, how it combines with other dietary supplements, and why it is important to take tryptophan during a pandemic.\n\nWhat is the difference between L-tryptophan and 5-HTP, and which amino acid is better?\n5-HTP (5-hydroxytryptophan) is an amino acid that is formed in the body during the breakdown of L-tryptophan. In nature, it is found in the seeds of Griffonia, but it is impossible to use them without special treatment. 5-HTP is completely used for the synthesis of the \"happiness hormone\" serotonin, while when taking L-tryptophan, only 20% is converted into serotonin, and the remaining 80% is spent on the production of melatonin, choline and niacin (vitamin B3).\n\nSince the body itself cannot produce tryptophan, but receives it only with protein food, with a lack of amino acids (and, accordingly, serotonin), appetite greatly increases, and, conversely, with normal hormone levels, saturation occurs faster, and the need for food decreases. This property of tryptophan is used in the treatment of eating disorders, in particular, bulimia.\n\nIf we compare amino acids in terms of effectiveness, then they both have a positive effect on the body. However, 5-HTP acts narrowly - it stimulates the production of serotonin only, and L-tryptophan, in addition to the \"hormone of happiness\", also promotes the synthesis of melatonin, choline and niacin, that is, it has a broader effect and can be used to solve more tasks.\n\nHow does L-tryptophan combine with other supplements and medications?\nIt is better to take all1 L-tryptophan together with vitamins B6, B5 and ascorbic acid, as they enhance the positive effect of the amino acid on the nervous system.\n\nTaking tryptophan with nicotinic acid accelerates its processing and provides a faster action.\n\nIn case of sleep disorders, a good effect is given by the combination of tryptophan with soothing herbs: motherwort, hops, ashsholtsia, passionflower.\n\nThese substances can be taken separately, but it is much more convenient to take complex products that include these components.\n\n\"Tryptophan\" from the company \"Evalar\" contains L-tryptophan, vitamins B6 and B5. It can be taken to support the body under high physical and emotional stress, apathy, irritability and anxiety.\n\nAnother product of the Sleep Formula company, in addition to L-tryptophan and B vitamins, contains phyto-melatonin, extracts of hops, passionflower, ashsholtsia and griffonia. Thanks to this composition, the capsules \"Sleep Formula\" are chosen for soothing and hypnotic effects.\n\nWith caution,2 L-tryptophan should be taken together with antidepressants, hypnotics, neuroleptics and anxiolytics, as they enhance the sedative effect of each other. It is not recommended to take tryptophan together with alcohol.\n\nHow does L-tryptophan affect eating habits and weight loss?\nAs we have already said, tryptophan comes along with protein food. When there is a shortage of it, the body sounds the alarm and \"demands\" protein: we begin to consume products containing this amino acid in large quantities. On the other hand, a serotonin deficiency caused by a lack of tryptophan leads to a decrease in mood and irritability, and we begin to eat stress. If this condition continues for a long time, it is likely to develop an eating disorder, and sometimes it can lead to obesity. To avoid this, tryptophan is taken in preventive courses.\n\nAlso, this amino acid can help those who are already overweight. The effect of tryptophan on eating habits and weight loss has been confirmed by clinical studies3. For example, an experiment conducted by a group of scientists, in which 19 obese women participated, showed that taking tryptophan at a dose of 8 mg / kg per day leads to a decrease in food intake and, as a result, to weight loss.\n\nThe use of L-tryptophan in sleep disorders and depressive states\n\nL-tryptophan is excellent at solving problems with sleep disorders. It facilitates falling asleep, increases the duration, improves the quality of sleep.\n\nTrials were also conducted5, which proved the effectiveness of tryptophan in depressive states. For example, two studies involving a total of 64 patients with a confirmed diagnosis of depression have shown that taking tryptophan helps to reduce the symptoms of the disease.\n\nAnother study6 has shown that tryptophan can be used in combination with SSRIs (selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors) to treat depression in cancer patients who take Interferon-alpha.\n\nWhy is it important to take L-tryptophan in the autumn-winter period?\nIn the cold season, the number of colds increases sharply. Immunity is weakening, and he needs additional support. L-tryptophan can also help here, because it stimulates the production of melatonin, a hormone that not only regulates sleep, but also has antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties.\n\nMelatonin is produced by the body under the influence of sunlight. In summer, when there is a lot of sun, we do not lack melatonin, but in autumn and winter its deficiency is observed in most people. It is possible to stimulate the natural production of melatonin by taking dietary supplements with L-tryptophan. Of course, it does not guarantee 100% protection against viral infections, but it will help the body cope with the disease faster.\n\nHow can L-tryptophan help with coronavirus infection?\nThe effect of L-tryptophan on melatonin production can be used for the prevention and treatment of COVID-19.\n\nThus, a study by 7 Brazilian scientists from the University of Sao Paulo has shown that melatonin, which is produced in the lungs, is able to act as a barrier against coronavirus infection. In the course of several experiments, scientists have discovered the ability of melatonin to interfere with the expression of genes responsible for encoding proteins by which the virus enters the cells of the nasopharynx and lungs. Due to this feature, melatonin stops the process of infection of lung tissues, and even if the virus enters the body, the disease proceeds in a milder form.\n\nAlso, science has long known the property of melatonin to reduce the production of cytokines that cause inflammation. One of the severe complications of COVID-19 is a cytokine storm, when the body releases an excessive amount of cytokines, thereby killing itself.\n\nCourse intake of L-tryptophan stimulates the production of melatonin, which can prevent severe complications of coronavirus infection.\n\nProducts with L-tryptophan from the Evalar company\nIn the assortment of the Evalar company there are two products containing L-tryptophan: \"Tryptophan\" and \"Sleep Formula\".\n\nThe composition of \"Tryptophan\" in addition to the amino acid itself includes vitamins B5 and B6. The course reception of \"Tryptophan\" can reduce anxiety, improve emotional state, normalize sleep and cheer up. The product is sold in easy-to-take capsules. For adults, it is enough to take 1-2 capsules 2 times a day to make up for the deficiency of L-tryptophan. The duration of admission is at least one month. If necessary, you can continue taking Tryptophan.\n\nThe composition of the \"Sleep Formula\" is specially designed for people who have trouble sleeping. The product includes L-tryptophan, phyto-melatonin, extracts of soothing herbs: passionflora, hops, ashsholtsia, griffonia, vitamins of group B. Regular intake of the \"Sleep Formula\" can contribute to a quick fall asleep and a restful sound sleep. It is enough for adults to take 2 capsules before going to bed for 1 month, if desired, the \"Sleep Formula\" can be taken for a longer time.\n\nImportant! Products with L-tryptophan are contraindicated during pregnancy and lactation, as well as with individual intolerance to the components included in their composition. It is recommended to consult a doctor before use.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_11_Lutein">Lutein is the most common carotenoid found in vegetables such as broccoli, Brussels sprouts, spinach, pumpkin. Its antioxidant properties are also more studied compared to other carotenoids. Lutein is the main pigment of the macula (macula), the area of the most accurate focusing of light rays and the best perception of light stimuli, i.e. the area of the best vision. \n\nLutein serves as a natural eye shadow, protecting the retina from the aggressive effects of the ultraviolet spectrum of sunlight. As we age, our eyes gradually lose lutein; researchers believe that this leads to increased damage to the retina by sunlight and, subsequently, to macular degeneration. It is clear that an increase in the content of lutein in food can reduce the risk of developing this pathology in adults. In addition, lutein is able to protect the lens from adverse effects, slowing the development of cataracts.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_12_Copper">Copper is one of the most important essential (vital) trace elements. In the adult human body, the copper content is approximately 100-200 mg, while about 50% of all copper is in the muscles, and another 10% in the liver.\n\nThe role of copper in the body is huge. First of all, it takes an active part in the construction of many proteins and enzymes we need, as well as in the processes of growth and development of cells and tissues. By participating in the synthesis of collagen, which is necessary for the formation of the protein skeleton of skeletal bones, copper makes our bones healthy and strong. For people with fragile bones and prone to fractures, it is often enough to introduce copper supplements into the diet – and fractures stop, as minerals stop being washed out, bone tissue strengthens, and the development of osteoporosis is prevented.\n\nThanks to copper, our blood vessels take the right shape, remaining strong and elastic for a long time. Copper contributes to the formation of elastin, a connective tissue that forms an inner layer that performs the function of a vascular framework.\n\nTogether with ascorbic acid, copper supports the immune system in an active state, helping it to protect the body from infections; enzymes responsible for protecting the body from free radicals also contain copper in their composition. Copper is especially needed to maintain the structure of the enzyme superoxide dismutase, which has a powerful antioxidant effect. This enzyme plays an important role in preventing premature aging of the skin - it is responsible for the integrity of cells, so it is often included in the most effective anti-aging cosmetics. The firmness and elasticity of the skin is maintained with the help of collagen – it also contains copper.\n\nCopper is of great importance for hematopoiesis, it is one of the elements that synthesize erythrocytes and leukocytes. It also transports iron, and if there is not enough copper, then iron will accumulate where it is not needed.\n\nCopper plays a very important role for blood vessels. It gives them the right shape, elasticity and strength.\n\nLack of copper can be the cause of frequent fractures, as it is an important component of the protein skeleton of bones.\n\nCopper in the human body plays another very important role - it destroys infections. History knows many confirmations of this. During the plague and cholera epidemics, people working in copper mines or factories were the least likely to get sick. By the way, such people also suffer from oncological diseases less than others.\n\nIt is worth noting that copper is famous for its medicinal properties and is widely used in folk medicine. Here are some examples.\n\nWith a bruise or hematoma, you need to attach a copper nickel to the damaged place, then the pain will pass, and there will be no bruise left.</string>
    <string name="supplements_fill_13_VitaminB">Water-soluble vitamin vitamin B1 is called an antineuritic vitamin, which characterizes its main effect on the body. Thiamine cannot accumulate in the body, so it is necessary that it enters the body daily.\n\nVitamin B1 is necessary for the normal functioning of every cell in the body, especially for nerve cells. It stimulates the brain, is necessary for the cardiovascular and endocrine systems, for the metabolism of acetylcholine, which is a chemical transmitter of nervous excitement. Thiamine normalizes the acidity of gastric juice, the motor function of the stomach and intestines, increases the body\'s resistance to infections. It improves digestion, normalizes the work of muscles and the heart, promotes the growth of the body and participates in fat, protein and water metabolism.  Thiamine is involved in the process of converting glucose into energy.\n\nThiamine is found mainly in grain products, bran. They are rich in bread made from coarse flour, cereals (buckwheat, oatmeal, millet), peas, beans, soy, brewer\'s yeast, liver, pork, veal.\n\nSigns of deficiency: increased fatigue, loss of strength, paresthesia, muscle pain, polyneuritis, intestinal atony, decreased myocardial contractility, heart failure, cardiac arrhythmias. In severe cases, paresis and paralysis of skeletal muscles occur. \n\nThe daily requirement of an adult for thiamine is 1.5 mg.</string>
    <string name="nootropics_fill_1" translatable="false">Coffee beans contain caffeine, vitamin PP, vitamin P, essential oils, as well as more than three dozen different organic acids, including malic, citric, acetic, coffee, oxoline, chlorogenic, pyruvic. Caffeine is the most important alkaloid of coffee beans, successfully used in medical practice. It excites the central nervous system, causing an improvement in metabolism, increased respiration, blood circulation, and increased vital activity of all body tissues.\n\nVitamin PP (nicotinic acid) is part of the enzymes that provide cellular respiration, is needed for the release of energy from carbohydrates and fats, is necessary for protein metabolism. Nicotinic acid affects the cardiovascular and nervous systems, it is necessary to maintain a healthy skin condition. Under the influence of nicotinic acid, the work of the stomach and pancreas is normalized. Vitamin P strengthens the walls of blood vessels well. In addition, potassium, calcium, sodium, iron, sulfur, phosphorus, nitrogen, magnesium, chlorine were found in coffee.\n\nThe characteristic aroma of roasted coffee is given by essential oils. The terpenes and phenol products contained in them have a certain antiseptic (antimicrobial) effect.\n\nChlorogenic acid is found in significant amounts only in coffee beans. Promotes good digestion and rapid \"evacuation\" of food from the stomach. Chlorogenic acid, like caffeine, acts on the central nervous system, circulatory, respiratory systems, digestion, etc.\n\nFeatures\n\nCoffee significantly accelerates the processes of assimilation and digestion of food, stimulating the secretion of gastric juice. Caffeine activates the consumption of oxygen by tissues and accelerates the breakdown of fats. Coffee has a strong diuretic (diuretic) effect. Removes excess fluid from the body, thereby relieving swelling.\n\nApplication\n\nCoffee promotes weight loss. The caffeine contained in it accelerates the metabolic processes in the body, regulates appetite, thereby reducing the portion of food eaten. Coffee miraculously reduces the caloric load on the digestive system by slowing down the processing of carbohydrates and lipids. Caffeine extracted from coffee tree beans stimulates metabolism and accelerates the breakdown of fats not only when used internally, but also when applied topically. Coffee promotes weight loss, improves blood circulation in the tissues, thereby reducing the risk of cellulite.\n\nCoffee has a versatile beneficial effect on the skin. It tones, increases elasticity, moisturizes, has anti-inflammatory properties, protects the skin from ultraviolet radiation, reduces pores. In addition, this product tends to have a lifting and anti-cellulite effect.</string>
    <string name="nootropics_fill_2">Choline is an aminoethyl alcohol containing 3 methyl groups at the nitrogen atom.\n\nCholine is a syrupy liquid with strongly pronounced alkaline properties.\n\nMetabolism\n\nCholine comes from food. It is partially destroyed by the intestinal microflora (with the formation of trimethylamine). With a high content of choline in the diet, it is absorbed by diffusion, with a low content - by active transport. In enterocytes, choline is phosphorylated.\n\nFrom the intestine, phosphocholine (and partially free choline) in the composition of lipoproteins with blood is carried through the tissues, where it is included in the metabolism.\n\nBiochemical functions:\n\nCholine is a metabolic precursor of an important neurotransmitter, acetylcholine.\n\nPhosphocholine, activated by CDP, is used for the synthesis of phosphatidylcholine (lecithin). In addition to participating in the synthesis of lecithin, choline is necessary for the synthesis of another lipid – sphingomyelin, which is formed by the transfer of choline from phosphatidylcholine to ceramide.\n\nCholine is a donor of methyl groups in transmethylation reactions (for example, betaine formed during choline oxidation serves as a source of methyl groups in methionine synthesis reactions).\n\nHypovitaminosis\n\nThe manifestation of choline deficiency in humans has not been described. In animals, fatty infiltration of the liver, hemorrhage of the kidneys and damage to blood vessels (especially coronary vessels) are noted.</string>
    <string name="bundles_fill_0">The listed substances are most likely suitable for beginners who are just getting acquainted with nootropics, or, perhaps, more experienced nootropics in conjunction with strong substances to stabilize the effect. I\'m a beginner, so I can\'t compare the effect of drugs with anything.\nI will describe the effects of L-Theanine and its links with Caffeine by leaps and bounds, but in general, since the sensations were similar throughout the course. And yet, when you read the description of the effects of the type \"the head has become clearer and lighter,\" feel free to divide it into two, since in words the sensations are transmitted stronger than they actually are.\n\nTo begin with, I will tell you about the solo use of L-Theanine (300 mg twice a day: in the morning and in the afternoon). Some may not notice the effect the first time. The effect of the drug occurs very smoothly and quite imperceptibly. But when the effect disappears completely (about 4-5 hours after taking it), you will remember and feel the effect of L-Theanine from memory. It is known that the substance is contained in green tea, although in small doses. It is an amino acid, it is similar to both glutamate and GABA. Glutamate is the most common excitatory neurotransmitter in the nervous system of vertebrates, GABA is an inhibitory neurotransmitter of the nervous system. Hence, indeed, there is a feeling of some not very noticeable composure during work and at the same time a sense of calm. Personally, I noticed most of all that I stopped being distracted by noise and conversations around when I was busy with something, the feeling that previously annoying sounds became less annoying and distracting (but at 300 mg. not much, make no mistake). This effect is also associated with an increase in alpha-wave activity of the brain, which occurs in a person in a calm state while focusing on an object that does not require mental effort. And yet, it is during mental work that L-Theanine helps, this will be discussed below on the example of a large dose.\nYou can periodically eat a little chocolate bars or something similar, given that Theanine increases the utilization of glucose in the brain. After the onset of the effect, you start to feel less nervous, others are unlikely to notice changes in you, but you will feel that you have begun to suffer a little less from stress. More often it manifests itself in exciting moments. If earlier in such situations completely unnecessary thoughts could get into your head (as happens with me), which also distracted you from solving the problem, then with L-Theanine, even if they appear, they will not distract you so much. I didn\'t really notice an increase in mood due to an increase in dopamine levels, but I felt a slight feeling of clarity and lightness in my head, probably it was dopamine that caused it.\nTheanine also dilates blood vessels, with good dosages (about 1000 mg.), there is a pleasant feeling of a rush of blood to the head. Sometimes it becomes fascinating to play around and feel the tide as soon as you start solving something) Let me remind you, the effect comes slowly, within 1 hour (if taken in capsules), so you will have to plan the reception in advance. We get that from 300 mg. three effects are more or less felt: you are less distracted from work by the noise around, your head seems to become lighter and clearer (not always), and you will become a little more stable or calm in stressful situations.\n\nAbout the method of reception.\nI made 40 capsules of 300 mg. Theanine, so that in some situations it would be more convenient to take. This is uneconomical, so I advise you to either add something else to the capsule (for example, Caffeine, 5-HTP, NALT ...), or dissolve it in water.\n\nIf the effect of 300 mg. L-Theanine will not be enough for you (most likely it will be), then you can increase it to 1000-1500 mg. and drink, dissolving in water (preferably 1 time a day).\n- Now I just took 1000 mg. and I can say that reading and thinking about the text, I literally immerse myself in it, of course, this does not manifest itself as the often described \"tunnel vision\" or something similar, no, everything happens very naturally. It seems that this was supposed to be the case, because I\'m just doing business: I\'m writing a text and rereading it. But no, it\'s noisy enough around, and besides, I have some plans that I\'ve already forgotten about... there was only a quiet entertaining work on the article. This can be called concentration against the background of calm. By the way, fans of flying in the clouds will like it, you will be able to immerse yourself in your thoughts, periodically pulling yourself up and realizing how you flew away... almost like when I was a kid. I\'ll make a reservation right away, Theanine will not affect the quality of thoughts, fantasies or anything else. If you decide to take such a large dose, then I advise you to do it not often, no more than three times a week. Although maybe such a dosage will not make it worse, but on the contrary, only better, I do not know.- I think this part of the review turned out to be the most important and rational in terms of the use of the substance (because for some reason, the dosages recommended by all articles and many reviews are 100-200 mg. most will call placebo)...I do not exclude that 100-200 mg will work well on you.\n\nNow about L-Theanine (300-400 mg./2 times a day) + Caffeine (200-300 mg. / 2 times a day). Important: I used this bundle no more than three times a week, so as not to develop tolerance to Caffeine. It is known that these two substances act synergistically. L-Theanine should remove such side effects of Caffeine as increased heart rate and increased blood pressure, as well as eliminate the feeling of fatigue after Caffeine withdrawal. Indeed, I did not notice this slight fog in my head and dispersion after the end of the action of Caffeine. There was also, as someone said, no \"bad energy\" from Caffeine.\nI was doing sports under this bundle more energetically, and, what is very noticeable, there was simply no fatigue after training, that is, at all) My friend also noted this effect. The same applies to mental stress. But don\'t waste all your energy like crazy, it\'s dangerous. If, while exercising under Caffeine, you notice that you have started to \"get sick\", stop smoothly, do not sit down, catch your breath a little (even if you don\'t want to), just in case, eat or drink something sweet to restore energy and drink water. I overtrained like that once, the sensations appeared quite sharply: there was weakness in the body, trembling in the legs, hunger and thirst broke through. I have (I admit, stupidly) this coincided with the moment of reduced immunity and winter vitamin deficiency, which is why I got such a thing with a load slightly above average. By the way, many people know, but I remind you: you should always drink more water and eat more vitamins (Vitrum®, etc.), carbohydrates (bananas, pasta, brown rice, oatmeal, etc.), proteins (eggs, chicken, etc.), fats (nuts, various oils, etc.), eating any nootropics. It is important that there is an effect and there is no headache (I think it is not necessary to write about choline). For example, I didn\'t even need to force myself to drink a lot of water, the body itself demanded what it needed, and I easily drank 3 bottles of water (about 1.5 liters in total) for 4 hours of the substances\' action. This applies to both the solo L-Theanine and the bundle. I can also say about the effect that Caffeine adds a little focus and speed in decision-making, that is, if someone needs activity to the calming effect of Theanine, then Caffeine will come in handy. And the most interesting thing is that already in the first days of admission I adjusted my sleep regime. I, like many in our time, had a problem: I could not (precisely could not) fall asleep in time to get enough sleep. Probably, the excess of information received during the day or artificial lighting affects. I have to wake up at 7:30, but I fall asleep at 1:00. I do not have enough sleep time, and I very often go sleepy in the first half of the day, which is why I sometimes get stupid) So, maybe solo L-Theanine, maybe its combination with Caffeine adjusted my regime so that I began to want to sleep at 22:00, which is why I started to get enough sleep. Perhaps it only affected me this way, but I still advise you to try L-Theanine if there is the same problem. So, the most noticeable effects after adding Caffeine are: activity during sports, lack of fatigue after training and a little more concentration.\n\nIn short, you probably noticed how often I used the word \"a little\" when describing the action of Theanine. From this we conclude that L-Theanine is unlikely to be suitable for improving one\'s abilities and achieving more or less significant goals. It can be taken as a \"permanent\" nootropic (taking advantage of the absence of harm with prolonged use) as a mild sedative (anti-stress) or as an excellent supplement to Caffeine.\n\nA small addition (February).\nRecently caught SARS. The temperature was 39, now recovered, but there is an asthenic syndrome. This is the same state when performance is reduced, the feeling of a certain \"renunciation of the world\", the feeling that YOU seem to be talking, but the thoughts of your speech seem to arise separately from you, without your control; it turns out that sometimes you are talking some nonsense. And then I accidentally discovered another benefit from Theanine. After reading a medical article about this syndrome, I found evidence that it can be treated with various sedatives, nootropics, etc., in particular, they called the drug Tenoten. I decided that L-Theanine might be suitable and took 500 mg. The condition really got a little better, this absent-mindedness and \"unconsciousness\" decreased by about half. Most likely, the substance has adjusted some processes in the brain, as the condition has become slightly better than before, even after the cessation of the substance.</string>
    <string name="bundles_fill_1">LEGAL psychoactive mushroom - Fly agaric. In particular, we will talk about Red Fly Agaric and its main components! As usual, no bullshit, just facts backed up by medical research.\nImmediately it is worth noting that outwardly the red fly agaric is similar to some other deadly mushrooms (1 , 2 , 3). And he himself is very toxic (4 , 5 , 6 ). So the information is for reference only.\nFly agaric has long been surrounded by various myths. It was especially popular in Sibir and also among berserkers, these are the ancient German and Scandinavian wars, who, according to legends, liked to eat fly agarics before battles. And what is so special about this mushroom?\nIbotenic Acid and Muscimol\nMuscimol is a psychoactive substance, Ibotenic acid is a poison. Both of these substances are present in Red Fly Agaric (7). Muscimol is also a product of decarboxylation of ibotenic acid. That is, ibotenic acid becomes a muscimol. This happens more often by drying the mushroom. And a poorly dried fly agaric, thus, becomes more of a poison than what you have heard about fly agarics. And these same muscimol and ibotenic acid are changeable in each mushroom. And most of them are in the hat, according to one Japanese study of \'93 (8). So a brief digression: raw fly agaric is a hallucinogen and poison, dried is a hallucinogen and, to a lesser extent, poison.\nI will immediately inform the fly agaric experts that yes, you better fumble how to cook it. But drying and sometimes cooking, more often comes across in honey articles. And there is a risk that the mushroom will affect each person in its own way. In 2005, a case of dry fly agarics was described in Poland, where out of 5 people, 1 girl lost consciousness and was hospitalized (9). Everything was fine with the rest.\nThere is no antidote, except that activated charcoal and gastric lavage can work, if not so much time has passed. It is the symptoms that are treated more often.\nAnd the 3rd substance, the gray cardinal fly agaric - Mannitol. It\'s something like mushroom sugar, a carbohydrate. So the more of it– the more muscimol will penetrate through the BBB - protection of the brain (10). And yes, its quantity is also variable. So fly agaric is a hard roulette with 3 unstable parameters, one of which is poison, another is a hallucinogen, the third is an amplifier of everything.\nNeurotransmitters\nFly agaric is not at all like psilocybin mushrooms, a completely different principle of operation.\nIbotenic acid itself is close to Glutamate, has affinity with NMDA and its metabotropic receptors [11]. This means it rather speeds up the brain.\nMuscimol, on the contrary, is an agonist of the GABA-A receptor (12 , 13). Adds confidence and mood. Alcohol and benzodiazepines, by the way, also modulate, make this receptor more active. Muscimol is also a partial agonist of the GABA-C receptor (14). They are similar to each other (15).\n\nMuscimol can inhibit MAO, it is an enzyme that regulates the destruction of our favorite Dopamines, Phenylethylamines, Norepinephrine (16, 17), thereby increasing them. MAO inhibitors as well as antidepressants are used.\nHere is an example of an old report on changes in activity after the introduction of muscimol (18). It is clear that this has been studied on animals, but the dynamics of change can be taken into account. It can be seen here that there is a decrease in acetylcholinesterase, in addition to MAO, and it destroys acetylcholine. Consequently, there will be more acetylcholine, clarity of thinking.\nIn short, fly agaric changes the balances in almost all major neurotransmitters. You will become more energetic and driven, with increased courage and distorted, but clear perception of the world, well, or stupidly poisoned.)\nLet\'s learn more about the effects!\nEffects\nNow it becomes clear that the action is too unstable and individual) If you cook poorly – your effects: nausea, hallucinations, headaches, and eventually - an ambulance. If you cook well, then some depersonalization, when you feel like you are not in your body, an unconventional view of the world, comparable to alcohol, but with sober thoughts and without impaired coordination, a little more courage and confidence, an anti-anxiety effect. Distortions in the perception of size, color, distance and depth, like Van Gogh\'s paintings.\nIn general, fly agaric effects are often compared just with alcohol.\nIt is also reported about the strengthening of muscimol with Taurine. So it is impossible to interfere with energy drinks or alcohol (19).\nFor medical purposes, it can be used for Parkinson\'s. Fly agaric reduces tremor, but does not affect speech (20)\nIn general, death from fly agaric is rare. But various psychoses up to 5 days after admission, even after loss of consciousness, are constantly dotted in reports (21 , 22).\nAccording to the correct dosages, it is difficult to say something. In some data, it is said about 0.1 mg / kg of muscimol for a person, this is 6-10 mg. This is about 1 dry cap of fly agaric or 5-10 g (23). In others - both smaller and larger dosages.\nThe first effects occur after 30 minutes with a peak after 3 hours. Side effects can persist for up to several days.\nResult:\n- Red fly agaric is too variable both in terms of the content of the components and the time of year of collection.\n- 2 main substances in it: Ibotenic acid - poison and Muscimol - psychedelic.\n- Works by reducing the activity of MAO and Acetylcholinesterase. It affects the GABA and Glutamate system. And how this explosive mixture will work on a particular person is not clear.\n- The main effects are similar to alcohol intoxication, only the hallucinogenic component is higher and without impaired coordination, but this is in an ideal scenario.</string>
</resources>